Richard Ghrist II

Cleveland, OH | 330.993.0105 <u>rickyghrist.com</u> <u>ricky.ghrist@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

Software Engineer and Application Developer with 4+ years of experience in full stack technologies while practicing SCRUM. I am focused on developing meaningful and correct solutions, improving agile methods and mentoring. My most experienced languages are python, .net, t-sql, and react.js.

EXPERIENCE

OnShift, Cleveland, OH

May 2019 - Present

Software Developer

Supported legacy python applications and worked on the .net rewrite of those projects. Worked directly with VP's of customer success to ensure customer satisfaction.

- Team lead of 7 for the .net core rewrite of an existing python legacy application
- Tech lead for the existing engagement application being rewritten
- Laid groundwork for the Auth0 implementation to replace our homegrown SSO solution
- Worked with Ops to use the Releases in Azure DevOps to replace our Jenkins and Ansible usage by 75%
- Team/Tech lead of 6 for the Time and Attendance project in MongoDb, React and .Net
- Successfully architected and implemented database designs, service bus usage, and azure function usage across the product floor

OnShift, Cleveland, OH

Dec 2018 - May 2019

Associate Software Developer

Engagement web application that used python, react, postgres, AWS and made use of a micro service architecture with Kubernetes.

- Refactored the backend python code to improve our database call throughput by 30%
- Standardized React patterns being used (ver 15.x) and the usage of LaunchDarkly for new features
- Used AWS to manage our Kubernetes cluster, kinesis steams and Cloudwatch jobs
- Proposed RFC's and diagrams on our architecture which led to a .net core rewrite of the backend
- Used daily SCRUM practices and released every one to two weeks

TekSystems – National General Insurance, Independence, OH **Software Developer I**

May 2018 – Dec 2018

Renewals team that worked in C#, VB.Net, git and VSTS. Worked on a constant stream of issues generated on the business side with high priority deadlines. Implemented agile methods that resulted in higher team productivity.

- Worked in a waterfall shop with hard releases of every two weeks
- Implemented SOLID in our project that created a simpler code base with broken out dependencies
- Lead a unit test project that in two months, we went from 0% coverage to 45% of our system

MRI Software, Solon, OH

Mar 2017 – May 2018

Software Developer I

Educated and mentor 6-7 new hires monthly through technical skills classes including SOLID, OOP, and custom tooling.

- Reworked the entire renewal system for residential owning clients in the UK
- Minimized expenditures and wait times by completing bulk renewals two weeks ahead of time allowing the extra time to be used to remove 15% of client-reported defects in other areas of the program

EDUCATION

Kent State University, B.A Computer Science The Ohio State University, B.A Psychology May 2015 - May 2017 Aug 2010 - Dec 2014